http://www.emapsite.com/about-us/ethos/privacy/#cookie

emapsite - Privacy
We use cookies to improve your online experience and the service we offer. To accept cookies continue browsing as normal. Read our cookies policy for more information. X
Menu
Information / Help
Call emapsite on 0118 973 6883
View our video tutorials
View our webinars
Checking your notifications...
Contact us
Sign In
Mapping & Data
OS MasterMap & Detailed Mapping
PDF Site Plans
Groundsure Insight Reports
Aerial Imagery
Street-Level Mapping
Mapping & Data
The mapping you know, from OS and many others, plus a huge variety of unique location datasets you won’t find anywhere else…
View this section
Mapping Apps
Mapshop
Plans
Reports
Contractor Link
Marine
Express
Streets
Mapping Apps
Our apps give you access to all kinds of data – just the mapping you want, in the location data format you need…
View this section
Mapshop
Spatial Insights
Spatialise
Spatialise
Spatialise explained
Spatialise Solutions
Unique insights
Spatial Insights
Spatial data can reveal hidden value. See how we spatialise to solve age-old business problems in new ways…
View this section
Explore Markets
Energy and Infrastructure
Engineering and Environment
Insurance and Financial
Land and Property
Public Sector
Explore Markets
Our spatial data and mapping teams have the expertise to help businesses and organisations in the private and public sector…
View this section
About Us
About Us
Transform your Business
News and Views
Careers
Contact Us
About Us
emapsite – mapping and data specialists, map licensing experts, plus teams of spatialising experts all on hand to help you…
View this section
New Spatial Insights division launches at emapsite
Read article
Search here ...
Mapping & Data
OS MasterMap & Detailed Mapping
PDF Site Plans
Groundsure Insight Reports
Aerial Imagery
Street-Level Mapping
Backdrop Raster Mapping
3D and Terrain Data
Privacy Policy - May 2018
emapsite Ltd is committed to preserving the privacy of all visitors to our website at www.emapsite.com. Please read the following privacy policy to understand our legal basis and purpose for processing your personal data.
Processing your personal data
To process your data we must have a lawful basis to do so. The law allows for six ways to process your personal data. We will process your personal data where:
You have given consent to the processing of your personal data for one or more specific purposes;
It is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract;
It is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject;
It is necessary in order to protect your vital interests;
It is necessary for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in us;
It is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by us or by a third party, except where such interests are overridden by your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms which require protection of personal data.
We are committed to protecting your personal information and respecting your privacy. We process your personal data when you access our Sites and Services. These include:
Viewing or subscribing to our websites and social media functions.
Corresponding with us using services such as web contact forms, webchat facility, telephone, email or written letter.
Signing up to marketing material or newsletters.
Entering competitions or participating in discussion boards.
Applying for a job vacancy.
Purchasing, licensing or accessing products, including mobile applications (Apps).
Some of our Sites and Services may include additional terms and conditions under an applicable end-user license agreement or terms of use (EULA or Terms of Use).
We use your personal data in the following ways:
Provide you with personalised access to mapping and other geospatial data
Provide you with access to other emapsite services
Fulfil online payments or orders for any products you purchase through our online services
Provide you with information about other goods and services we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about, where you have consented to such communications
Provide you with promotions and and information about other goods and services we feel may interest you, where you have consented to such communications
Carry out our obligations from any contracts you have entered into with us
Conduct customer satisfaction surveys and market research
Process job vacancy applications and CVs
Respond to your enquiries and complaints
Notify you about changes to our products and services
Our legitimate interests
There are times when we will rely on legitimate interests to process personal data, particularly when it is not practical to obtain consent. We will always consider if it is fair and balanced to do so and if it is within your reasonable expectations. We will balance your rights and our legitimate interests to ensure that we use your personal information in ways that are not unduly intrusive or unfair. Examples are:
Reporting criminal acts and compliance with law enforcement agencies.
Internal and external audit for financial or regulatory compliance purposes
Statutory reporting
Maintenance of suppression lists
Customer satisfaction surveys and market research
Physical and network security
Work experience placements
Financial management and control
General administration
Categories of personal data you may give to us
Categories of personal data you give us includes:
Name
Address
Telephone number
Email address
Date of birth and age
User name and passwords to access our sites and services
Financial and credit card information
Personal profile description and photograph
Equality and diversity information
Location information
Your location information
We may use GPS technology or other technology to determine your current location in order to provide certain functionality to you as part of our site and services.
You can withdraw your consent to determine your current location at any time through your device setting
Your device information
Each time you visit or use our Sites and Services, we may automatically collect the following information:
Technical information, including the type of mobile device you use, a unique device identifier (for example, your Device's IMEI number, the MAC address of the Device's wireless network interface, or the mobile phone number used by the Device), mobile network information, your mobile operating system, the type of mobile browser you use, and/or time zone setting;
Details of your visits to any of our Sites and Services including, but not limited to, Internet protocol (IP) address used by your Device, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, whether this is required for our own billing purposes and the resources that you access (Log Information);
URL click stream information showing how users have reached our Site and Services and whether they access other third party sites via any external links.
We use the device information in the following ways:
To administer our site and services for troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes;
To improve our site and services to ensure that content is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your device;
To allow you to participate in interactive features of our sites and/or service, when you choose to do so;
As part of our efforts to keep our sites and services safe and secure;
To determine which features your device supports which assists our development strategy.
We use the Log information in the following ways:
Track the success of our products and services and our marketing activity.
Monitor data traffic and any patterns of use.
Ensure the content of our site and services are fit for purpose for which they are set up and to develop the experience of our users; monitor compliance with and enforce our Terms of Use or data licensing terms.
Information we pass to third parties and other data sharing
In order to facilitate your use of our site and services, we may have to share your personal data with third parties to provide elements of our site and services to you. We will provide your personal data to third parties when they need the data to perform particular functions in delivering our sites and services to you or as part of our regulatory compliance. These include:
Service providers acting as data processors, located in the UK and EU who provide data hosting facilities, IT and system administration services.
Service providers located in the UK and EU acting as data processors who administer our customer email service, webchat service, API Services.
Service providers where a device requires interaction with 3rd parties for registration of devices, 3rd party software and downloading of mapping tiles.
Service providers acting as a data processor for the facilitation of our recruitment processes.
HM Revenue & Customs, regulators and other authorities acting as processors or joint controllers based in the United Kingdom who require reporting of processing activities in certain circumstances.
We may disclose your personal information to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the Companies Act 2006.
Third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them.
If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal or regulatory obligation or request.
In order to enforce or apply the terms of a relevant EULA, our Terms of Use and other agreements or to investigate potential breaches; or
Protect the rights, property or safety of our group companies, our suppliers and/or our customers.
We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.
Data transfers to third countries
The data we collect from you may, on occasion, be processed at a destination outside the European Economic Area (EEA). It may also be processed by organisations operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. These organisations may be engaged in the fulfilment of your request, order or reservation, and the provision of support services.
Where we use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe.
Where we use providers based in the US, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between the Europe and the US.
We will take steps reasonably necessary to ensure there is an adequate level of protection of your data and that your data is treated securely and in accordance with our Privacy Policy.
Data security
Once it is within our control, we will do our utmost to ensure your personal data is processed in a way that ensures appropriate security from unauthorised or unlawful processing, accidental loss, destruction or damage.
We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.
Retaining your personal information
We will retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements. We may also retain your personal data for a reasonable period afterwards to allow us to respond to any follow up enquiries or complaints, or for as long as you remain a registered user of our products and services.
To determine appropriate retention periods for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.
In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes, we may use or store this information indefinitely without further notice to you.
In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see Right of Erasure below for further information.
Your data protection rights
Withdraw consent – Where we are using your personal information on the basis of your consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time.
Right to be informed – You have the right to be told how your personal information will be used. This policy document, and shorter summary statements used on our communications, are intended to be a clear and transparent description of how your data may be used.
Right of access – You can write to us asking what information we hold on you and to request a copy of that information. This is called a Subject Access Request. From 25 May 2018 we will have 30 days to respond to you once we are satisfied you have rights to see the requested records and we have successfully confirmed your identity. Please contact us if you wish to submit a Subject Access Request
Right of erasure – From 25 May 2018, you have the right to be forgotten (i.e. to have your personally identifiable data deleted). However, we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons, which will be notified to you. In some cases, we may recommend that we suppress you from future communications, rather than data deletion. Our Customer Services Team will be happy to advise you.
Right of rectification – If you believe our records are inaccurate you have the right to ask for those records concerning you to be updated. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected. We may need to verify the accuracy of the new data provided to us.
Right to restrict processing – In certain situations you have the right to ask for processing of your personal data to be restricted because there is some disagreement about its accuracy or legitimate usage.
Right to data portability – Where we are processing your personal data under your consent, the law allows you to request data portability from us to another service provider. This right is largely seen as a way for people to transfer their personal data from one service provider to another. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.
Right to object – You have an absolute right to stop the processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes. If you wish to amend your communication preferences you can do so on our Your Preferences page
Right to object to automated decisions – In a situation where a data controller is using your personal data in a computerised model or algorithm to make decisions “that have a legal effect on you”, you have the right to object. This right is more applicable to mortgage or finance situations. We do not undertake complex computerised decision making that produce legal effects.
Cookies
Cookies are small amounts of information, which we may store on your computer. Unless you have indicated your objection when disclosing your details to us, our system will issue cookies to your computer when you log on to the site. Cookies make it easier for you to log on to and use the site during future visits. They also allow us to monitor website traffic and to personalise the content of the site for you. You may set up your computer to reject cookies by following the relevant instructions, which can be found at www.aboutcookies.org.uk In that case, you may not be able to use certain features on our site. If you do not wish to receive cookies in the future, please let us know at info@emapsite.com
Changes to this policy
Any changes we may make to our Privacy Policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you. The new terms may be displayed on-screen and you may be required to read and accept them to continue your use of our services.
Contact
All comments, queries and requests relating to our use of your information are welcomed and should be addressed to info@emapsite.com
